[{"id": "5937eed608d98002fdd633d9", "question": "From which musical did \"One Night in Bangkok Makes a Hard Man Humble\" and \"I Know Him So Well\" come?", "answer": "Chess", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ce", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a1736c0f9723ab15cb39", "question": "The Ishtar Gate was the main entrance to which ancient city?", "answer": "Babylon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc4", "question": "What jazz legend's singing shattered the glass in the famous \"Is it live or is it Memorex?\" ads?", "answer": "Ella Fitzgerald's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb9", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional \"The Kings of Queens\" fraternity?", "answer": "All in the Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea8145ff048f679a45ac1f", "question": "What is the fastest ocean fish?", "answer": "Sailfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa4", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a899ca560d398dc9cf7a6a8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who are Hestia's six siblings?", "answer": "Demeter, Hera, Hades, Zeus, Poseidon, Chiron", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe765f7eec85e375820b27a", "question": "Which famous figures are featured on Prague\u2019s astronomical clock?", "answer": "The 12 Apostles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391dc", "question": "Who played Mr. White in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Harvey Keitel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c4", "question": "What element has the chemical symbol Au?", "answer": "Gold", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2d", "question": "Someone who raises false alarms is said to cry what?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394fc", "question": "In the TV series \"Doctor Who\", what does the acronym TARDIS stand for?", "answer": "Time and Relative Dimension in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d3", "question": "In which country was the singer Mika born?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937eb5b08d98002fdd633ad", "question": "Which three family members released an album titled \"Priority\" in 1979?", "answer": "The Pointer Sisters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7e3", "question": "The Benelux is a union in Western Europe that is comprised of what three neighboring countries?", "answer": "Belgium, The Netherlands, and Luxembourg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8a", "question": "What type of stuffed animal does an arctophile collect?", "answer": "Teddy bears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c859", "question": "What are the only two consecutive prime numbers?", "answer": "2 and 3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc1", "question": "What is divided by the Cassini Division?", "answer": "Saturn's rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e5", "question": "Who is Tippi Hedren's daughter?", "answer": "Melanie Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ae", "question": "What is the capitol of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe654eaae7e414034b5aead", "question": "Who originally said, \"The greatest trick the Devil ever pulled was convincing man he didn't exist\"?", "answer": "French poet Baudelaire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008e77cf842fa4c4ba96b2", "question": "What two parties fought in the \"Battle of Jutland\"?", "answer": "United Kingdom and Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d7c52596a59cbdfbd3ba", "question": "John Chapman was an amateur horticulturist better known under what name?", "answer": "Johnny Appleseed", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f84", "question": "What is the name of the son of the witch Sycorax?", "answer": "Caliban in The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad2", "question": "What word comes from the Greek for \"thick-skinned\"?", "answer": "Pachyderm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4b", "question": "How many morae are there in Japanese haiku?", "answer": "Seventeen", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fedd9cb6ce05a3942286d7c", "question": "What is the name of the last videogame console Sega released in the United States?", "answer": "Dreamcast was released in 1999.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133934f", "question": "What famous ex-boyfriend of Jennifer Aniston once guest-starred on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600244004be4723ccac2219f", "question": "Snowball and Napoleon are pigs who appear in which George Orwell novel?", "answer": "\"Animal Farm\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592eaf51f83302ff91e46492", "question": "What is the stage name of Roberta Joan Anderson?", "answer": "Joni Mitchell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f57eff048f679a45aad6", "question": "Which Crayola color was named by a five-year-old?", "answer": "Razzmatazz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396d9", "question": "What did Woodsy Owl often exclaim on TV in the 1970s and 1980s?", "answer": "Give a hoot! Don't pollute!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ace301dd7bf43be5e771", "question": "What company created Mr. Pibb?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5e", "question": "What artist, who died in 1986, was famous for her Southwestern paintings?", "answer": "Georgia O\u2019Keefe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea412bff048f679a45ab6d", "question": "What physical constant did Henry Cavendish first determine using two weights and a cantilever?", "answer": "Gravitational Constant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c801", "question": "What invisible \"color\" can bees see on flower petals?", "answer": "Ultraviolet, or Bee purple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25bdfb63e5727cf5a485d", "question": "What year did Cher release the single \"Believe\"?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cad9", "question": "What was the common archaic name for a giraffe?", "answer": "Camelopard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "596761082b59efe0e9417ea0", "question": "The fear of some unknown evil is called what?", "answer": "Panphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4e70006d333868d34d738", "question": "How many specific commandments regulating aspects of people's lives are there in the Bible in the Mosaic Law?", "answer": "613", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339307", "question": "What is Dr. Hannibal Lector's profession?", "answer": "Psychiatrist", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51c", "question": "What is Whisky distilled from?", "answer": "Fermented grain mash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c7", "question": "Who is the subject of Jean Anouilh's play \"L'Alouette\"?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf8", "question": "What J.D. Salinger character never found out where the ducks in Central Park go during the winter?", "answer": "Holden Caulfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323283bf195a31e15d7391", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation \"Coma Berenices\"?", "answer": "Berenice's Hair", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b8d47a2b42d4a3561a9ef9", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", who did Katchoo visit when she disappeared in Canada for 2 months?", "answer": "Emma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338da4", "question": "What author created the character of Tom Wingfield?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394ce", "question": "What TV spy often tried to pass himself off as a salesman for the Pontiac Greeting Card Company?", "answer": "Maxwell Smart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe734f2eec85e375820b240", "question": "What prison held Rudolf Hess after World War II?", "answer": "Spandau Prison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d54", "question": "What famous double negative is the first line in Pink Floyd's \"Another Brick in the Wall (Part II)\"?", "answer": "We don't need no education", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c2", "question": "Which son of Hypnos was the god of dreams?", "answer": "Morpheus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe131b0e39efa6330e0fed8", "question": "Where is the Museum of Pop Culture?", "answer": "Seattle, Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a8", "question": "What three colors are used in the flag of Texas?", "answer": "Red, white and blue", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde5223c6c6b019850c9a95", "question": "Britain annexed Hong Kong as a result of which war?", "answer": "The Opium War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d47438f8e329de4f87789a", "question": "The Bunya Pine tree is native to which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a8", "question": "What song is most famous for its suggestive chorus of \"Voulez-vous coucher avec moi (ce soir)\"?", "answer": "Lady Marmalade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f37", "question": "In \"The Arabian Nights\", the tale of Aladdin and his lamp is actually set in what non-Arabian country?", "answer": "China", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c0", "question": "What Western star rode a horse named Buttermilk?", "answer": "Dale Evans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb5", "question": "How many lines are in a sonnet?", "answer": "14", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cb70bfcf96e155acab35d27", "question": "What is Chiroptophobia?", "answer": "Fear of Bats", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fbaed8f0738315b1fb74e31", "question": "What spell was used to trick the Goblet in \"Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire\"?", "answer": "Confundus Charm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab1b7fbaab681b0929219a", "question": "What is BMW's name short for?", "answer": "Bayerische Motoren Werke", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d24", "question": "What popular children's character was used to write a book to explain Taoism?", "answer": "Winnie the Pooh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b830e662d71a5365101e", "question": "What is the name of the literary club founded by J.R.R. Tolkien while in Oxford as a professor?", "answer": "Inklings", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae9", "question": "The second video ever played on MTV was by what female artist?", "answer": "Pat Benatar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2ba", "question": "What year did the TV show \"30 Rock\" debut on TV?", "answer": "2006", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6012188763c99d48cd169af4", "question": "What flavor is Cointreau?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dcf", "question": "What future game show host was the first regular panelist on \"Match Game '73\"?", "answer": "Richard Dawson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aad", "question": "What popular children\u2019s book did Forrest Gump keep in his briefcase?", "answer": "Curious George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f719ca9e54d890926f6e2", "question": "In geography, what is a skerry?", "answer": "A small rocky island.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afba", "question": "Who was the last Viceroy to India?", "answer": "Lord Mountbatten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8b", "question": "Which US president survived two assassination attempts during the 20th century?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76d", "question": "What type of skin cancer starts in the pigment cells, often after too much sun exposure?", "answer": "Melanoma", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339603", "question": "What movie coined the phrase \"In space, no one can hear you scream\"?", "answer": "Alien", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133952d", "question": "Who portrayed James Bond in the 1965 film \"Thunderball\"?", "answer": "Sean Connery", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971dd8e89261e916c8e099e", "question": "Who played the title role in the 1990\u2019s TV show \"Grace Under Fire\"?", "answer": "Brett Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339383", "question": "How long does a replicant live for in the movie \"Blade Runner\"?", "answer": "Four years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e9a9febfabb9c85d8a97d", "question": "What is the fear of odors known as?", "answer": "Olfactophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73602eec85e375820b257", "question": "Abraham Lincoln, Julius Caesar, Tutankhamen and Osama bin Laden all suffered from what disorder?", "answer": "Marfan syndrome", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff141dbb0ee8c595b6d39a8", "question": "Rembrandt opened his first art studio at which age?", "answer": "19", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339100", "question": "What color was Rudolph the Reindeer's nose?", "answer": "Red", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a55820565ad31a57c7ca", "question": "What color were the first taxis in America?", "answer": "Red and green", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc1522469bb8041d07a089", "question": "Where is the famous haunted house located that was the subject of books and films following the murder of the DeFeo family?", "answer": "Amityville, Long Island, New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0aa", "question": "What kind of a head does a Criosphinx possess?", "answer": "Ram", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4a", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339058", "question": "Who wrote the epic poem \"Aeneid\"?", "answer": "Virgil", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d55", "question": "Emilio Estevez was originally cast in what other actor's role in \"The Breakfast Club\"?", "answer": "Judd Nelson's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0af61e662d71a53650fbc", "question": "Named after the Greek God of Wind, which musical instrument is played by passing an air current over its strings?", "answer": "Aeolian harp", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e79", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"Love and Marriage\" by Frank Sinatra as its theme song?", "answer": "Married...with Children", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e74", "question": "What superteam includes Thor, Iron Man, the Hulk, Ant-Man and the Wasp?", "answer": "The Avengers", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7ab8646490a8cc1a6e528c", "question": "What type of bear has a clear eyelid?", "answer": "Polar Bears", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5967613d2b59efe0e9417ea2", "question": "The song \"Good Girl\" was the 12th Top 20 hit for what artist?", "answer": "Carrie Underwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a4", "question": "What city is the TV show \"Sex and the City\" based in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7344eeec85e375820b232", "question": "Who was the only US president to not marry?", "answer": "James Buchanan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd47d7e83c707845b215d", "question": "Who is the world-famous writer and director of \"Seven Samurai\"?", "answer": "Akira Kurosawa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b153e662d71a53650fd0", "question": "Who founded Dumbledore's Army?", "answer": "Hermione Granger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f82901dd7bf43be5e841", "question": "Gnosiophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Knowledge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af93", "question": "General George H. Thomas was nicknamed the \"Rock of Chickamauga\" during what war?", "answer": "Civil War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d94", "question": "In the movie \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\", what animals dispose of Veruca Salt?", "answer": "Squirrels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b27", "question": "Who is credited with writing the first detective story, \"The Murders in the Rue Morgue\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fc2f265cee580c7f8fd1e52", "question": "Who said, \"Winners never quit, and quitters never win.\"?", "answer": "Vince Lombardi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdffc9f1cf6db9ac4808d01", "question": "What is the smallest country located entirely within the Himalayas?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389b9", "question": "Who took the role of Lysander in the Disney version of \"A Midsummer Night's Dream\"?", "answer": "Mickey Mouse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1b2", "question": "In 1961, who sent in troops to eject the Portuguese from their colony of Goa?", "answer": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600242004be4723ccac22180", "question": "Which Irish poet, born in 1865, was instrumental in the founding of the Abbey Theatre in Dublin?", "answer": "William Butler Yeats", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339630", "question": "Which TV show's theme song starts with the words \"Come and knock on my door...\"?", "answer": "Three's Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93a0f6bd93ce3a4e5f693", "question": "Who was the first scientist to observe live cells?", "answer": "Antonie van Leeuwenhoek", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389eb", "question": "What major comedy star played Garp in the movie adaptation of John Irvning's \"The World According to Garp\"?", "answer": "Robin Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c66e", "question": "Which have longer snouts - alligators or crocodiles?", "answer": "Crocodiles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5e147885dd42e4a67cb8d3eb", "question": "What model of car has a starring role as \"Eleanor\" in the 1974 film \"Gone in 60 Seconds\"?", "answer": "1973 Ford Mustang Mach 1", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c5df0775fa611bce67cd", "question": "The Chang Building in Bangkok, Thailand, was designed to look like what?", "answer": "Elephant -- AKA the Elephant Building, the skyscraper was intended to reflect the importance of elephants in Thai culture.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65916ae7e414034b5aefa", "question": "Pilgrims never called themselves Pilgrims, what were they?", "answer": "Sepratists", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29a", "question": "Who directed the 1996 film \"Escape from L.A.\"?", "answer": "John Carpenter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fde4ca2c6c6b019850c9a7d", "question": "How long did biblical Noah live after the flood?", "answer": "350 years", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd6a8236c0f9723ab15cb63", "question": "What is the best-selling beer in the U.S.?", "answer": "Bud Light", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a552683e1c6f9840ba3195", "question": "Where was the Armistice of 11 November 1918 signed?", "answer": "Compiegne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3589855db0d66a186cb54c", "question": "The Republic of Benin shares a border with which other African country to the east?", "answer": "Nigeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa3efbc73aa70ea0b70afa", "question": "Which natural feature is Michigan named after?", "answer": "Lake (The word \"Michigan\" is a French derivative of the Ojibwa word \"misshikama,\" which means \"large lake\" or \"large water\".)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c035", "question": "Who invented the Spinning Jenny?", "answer": "James Hargreaves", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa5", "question": "What superhero built a \"Fortress of Solitude\" at the North Pole?", "answer": "Superman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133987b", "question": "In Star Wars, Obi-wan Kenobi is introduced under what pseudonym?", "answer": "Ben", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b32362bbf195a31e15d73b8", "question": "What year was the character of Betty Crocker first introduced?", "answer": "1921", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51f", "question": "Which body joint includes the patella?", "answer": "Knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab74", "question": "Dhaka is the capital of which Asian country?", "answer": "Bangladesh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0e", "question": "Filmmaker Duncan Jones is the son of which British Glam Rock legend?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac73", "question": "The Bronze Age was characterized by the use of which malleable metal and one of its alloys?", "answer": "Copper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd89", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Megalon?", "answer": "Beetle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abea", "question": "Easter Island is a part of which South American country?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b323740bf195a31e15d73c3", "question": "Lisbon lies on which river?", "answer": "Tagus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "590678e5ff9c0647b50a804d", "question": "What month, in 2016, did the World Trade Organization announce an outbreak of the Zika virus?", "answer": "January", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab0", "question": "During the 1960's, what musician formed and fronted the band \"The Mothers of Invention\"?", "answer": "Frank Zappa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb7", "question": "Who wrote the 1971 novel \"The Exorcist\"?", "answer": "William Peter Blatty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b117", "question": "In American history, what 20th century decade is often described as \"Roaring\"?", "answer": "1920's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff5169eff04d658268c92f1", "question": "What activist organized the \"March of the Mill Children\" from Philadelphia to President Teddy Roosevelt's summer home in 1903?", "answer": "Mary Harris Jones -- She organized the march to demand an end to child labour.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a977", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Rajya Sabha?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fce", "question": "Where did Aristotle believe the seat of intelligence was?", "answer": "Heart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b812", "question": "What is the nickname of Alcatraz Prison?", "answer": "The Rock", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e80537de59ea584496fea9", "question": "Which dog is named for the German word for snout?", "answer": "Schnauzer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394d0", "question": "What is the title of the bugle tune sounded as the introduction to a horse race?", "answer": "First Call", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac13", "question": "Which ocean surrounds the Union of the Comoros?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fee", "question": "Who got his signature left-ear piercing in 1986, after interviewee Liza Minnelli encouraged him to do it?", "answer": "Ed Bradley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950a", "question": "What is the name of John Carpenter's first short movie?", "answer": "Revenge of the Colossal Beasts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba4c", "question": "What college football championship game has been held in Miami since 1935?", "answer": "Orange Bowl", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbf636ce05a3942286eff", "question": "The nightclub in the opening scene of the film \"Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom\" is called what?", "answer": "Club Obi-Wan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b38f06d333868d34d6d9", "question": "Which song produced a Christmas truce during World War I?", "answer": "\"Silent Night\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e8", "question": "What sport features snatches and clean jerks?", "answer": "Weightlifting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a778", "question": "What former Soviet Republic lies just across the Gulf of Finland from Finland?", "answer": "Estonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c852877e98cb977789e2", "question": "In which US state can you find George Vanderbilt's extravagant Biltmore Estate?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac9", "question": "Who portrays Tom Clancy's hero Jack Ryan in the movie \"The Sum of All Fears\"?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a4", "question": "Which US state was established by William Penn in 1681?", "answer": "Pennsylvania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b669", "question": "What automaker produced a luxury model named \"Imperial\" in 1926?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391fa", "question": "Who provided the voice for Maggie Simpson's first word, which none of her family heard her say?", "answer": "Elizabeth Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1f1", "question": "What year did Volkswagen debut the Golf?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133915d", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "Francis Ford Coppola", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339339", "question": "What actress played the role of Pamela Barnes Ewing on the TV show \"Dallas\"?", "answer": "Victoria Principal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b0f20565ad31a57c75b", "question": "In Nazi concentration camps, a pink triangle signified the prisoner as what?", "answer": "Homosexual", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f3057985aa2bc17b61b2ad2", "question": "What is the fear of smells or odors known as?", "answer": "Osmophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b450", "question": "The US was among several nations that sent troops to quell which 1900 uprising in China?", "answer": "The Boxer Rebellion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfea99dc5ec6cd98a832b", "question": "What word did Robert A. Heinlein introduce into the English language in his book \"Stranger in a Strange Land\"?", "answer": "In the 1961 science-fiction novel, Heinlein coined the term Grok, which means \"to understand intuitively or by empathy\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb5", "question": "What country\u2019s air force was destroyed on the ground on June 5, 1967?", "answer": "Egypt\u2019s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e7", "question": "What river divides Paris into the Right Bank and the Left Bank?", "answer": "The Seine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de7", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"kumquat\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bb356202627b8fe95581bdd", "question": "As of 2014, which country is the location of the second highest flagpole in the world after Saudi Arabia built a taller one in Jeddah?", "answer": "Tajikistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1c7", "question": "Which Disney film features the ballad \"Can You Feel the Love Tonight\"?", "answer": "The Lion King", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a899b4160d398dc9cf7a69b", "question": "Egg Fu is the enemy of what superhero?", "answer": "Wonder Woman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff670f552a821ff76ae8b23", "question": "Who invented \"Jell-O\"?", "answer": "Pearle Wait", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ce", "question": "Which one of your toes is also known as your \"hallux\"?", "answer": "Big toe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a902", "question": "What is the only US state whose two-letter postal code is two vowels?", "answer": "Iowa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389be", "question": "What country provides the setting for \"The King and I\"?", "answer": "Siam (Thailand)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a23b", "question": "Who released the 1970's album entitled \"Madman Across the Water\"?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909d154bb53d1af65886501", "question": "In which Canadian province would you find Christmas Island?", "answer": "Nova Scotia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72d", "question": "What is Santa's name in France?", "answer": "Pere Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc6536de0eb824d4052f7", "question": "What is the official state fruit of New Hampshire?", "answer": "Pumpkin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbd1", "question": "What is Pokemon an abbreviation of?", "answer": "Pocket Monster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b453", "question": "Which 19th century monarch ordered Buckingham House to be expanded into a royal palace?", "answer": "George IV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a0", "question": "How many minutes does it take to complete a 12 round boxing match?", "answer": "47 minutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b303", "question": "Who did Brazil name an official national treasure in 1962, so he wouldn't emigrate to Italy?", "answer": "Pele", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ba", "question": "Which is the fourth planet from the Sun?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339754", "question": "Who won an Oscar for her role as a call girl in the movie \"Klute\"?", "answer": "Jane Fonda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e68", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Yogi Bear?", "answer": "Daws Butler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c654", "question": "Which astronomer gave his name to a telescope launched into space in 1990?", "answer": "Edwin Hubble", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b447", "question": "What year did Joseph Merrick die?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e80433de59ea584496fea3", "question": "Who wrote the 1956 novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Dodie Smith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb5b77e83c707845b2120", "question": "What does a Maillard reaction refer to?", "answer": "Browning food while cooking", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be80", "question": "What's the only Grand Slam tennis event still played on grass?", "answer": "Wimbledon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa2", "question": "With what is sulfur and saltpeter mixed to make gunpowder?", "answer": "Charcoal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d16", "question": "What gangster movie was originally titled \"The Menace\" and eventually subtitled \"The Shame of the Nation\"?", "answer": "Scarface", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe93b446bd93ce3a4e5f6a1", "question": "According to Galileo's biographer, what tower did he climb to prove his \"Law of Falling Objects\" theory?", "answer": "Tower of Pisa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe659a4ae7e414034b5af03", "question": "What natural human bodily fluid did Romans use as mouth wash because of the presence of ammonia in it?", "answer": "Urine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4c", "question": "Krist Novoselic is best known as being the bass player for what former band?", "answer": "Nirvana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a0a4cf93664eb10486b9", "question": "What year was the Norwegian non-profit organization, \"Norse Federation\" founded?", "answer": "1907", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600f7475a9e54d890926f6f7", "question": "Buchaechum is a traditional Korean what?", "answer": "Fan dance", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b76f", "question": "A \"brigantine\" is a type of what?", "answer": "Sailing ship", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d076cb870e6f05ba60085e", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Taming of the Shrew\", who is the shrew's more desireable sister?", "answer": "Bianca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071bde3745b36be73039c5", "question": "Who is Tony Chu\u2019s partner in the comic series \"Chew\"?", "answer": "John Colby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58bb358fe368446ca7bd6854", "question": "What is an Affogato?", "answer": "Gelato, or ice cream, topped with hot espresso", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c48c", "question": "What garden flower's name literally means \"nose twister\"?", "answer": "Nasturtium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdc0d3a469bb8041d07a05a", "question": "What claims to be the first self-balancing electric transportation device?", "answer": "Segway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b06", "question": "Who teaches \"Charms\" in Hogwarts?", "answer": "Professor Flitwick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a0", "question": "In what decade was the voting age in the US lowered to 18?", "answer": "1970's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c289", "question": "What is xenophobia?", "answer": "Fear of strangers or foreigners", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c59", "question": "Who was the faithful wife of Ulysses in Homer\u2019s \"Odyssey\"?", "answer": "Penelope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34b", "question": "Which African country was the setting for the TV serial \"The Flame Trees of Thika\"?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a4", "question": "When did Sid Vicious join the Sex Pistols?", "answer": "1977", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba78", "question": "How many strings does the typical mandolin have?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942e", "question": "What is the name of the school in the 1989 movie \"Dead Poets Society\"?", "answer": "The Welton Academy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb582f5dad637d903c880f", "question": "What animal is considered to be symbolic of Venice?", "answer": "Lion -- The Lion of St. Mark is a symbol that appears throughout the city.  It honors St. Mark, who is the patron saint of Venice.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339687", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", who is Chief Wiggum's wife?", "answer": "Sarah Wiggum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f3d9ff048f679a45aac4", "question": "Who coined the term dark energy?", "answer": "Michael S. Turner", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea7c69ff048f679a45abf7", "question": "What color did the inside of watermelons used to be?", "answer": "Pale green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396cf", "question": "Who is the teacher of the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles?", "answer": "Master Splinter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16accf7c52aae91cc07e1", "question": "Which state is home to Australia's highest mainland mountain?", "answer": "New South Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339db0", "question": "What is the name of the American musician best known as the lead singer of the rock band Nirvana?", "answer": "Kurt Cobain", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1dc", "question": "Which US president lived in Monticello?", "answer": "Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb51", "question": "Founded in 1911, what company was first known as the Computing Tabulating  Recording Corporation?", "answer": "IBM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ddc306d333868d34d708", "question": "In which developed nation was unemployment the highest in the 1920's?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a3", "question": "What is the term for the official record of a dog\u2019s ancestry?", "answer": "Pedigree", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c679", "question": "What is the main source of food for the Bald Eagle?", "answer": "Fish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25737b63e5727cf5a4842", "question": "What decade saw the rapid growth in 3D puzzle popularity, largely driven by the Puzz 3D brand?", "answer": "1990s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b703", "question": "What is an albatross in golf scoring?", "answer": "3 under par", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cde", "question": "What does Marvel Comics character Howard the Duck often have in his mouth?", "answer": "A cigar", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339333", "question": "On the TV show \"Hogan's Heroes\", what is Sergeant  Schultz's catchphrase?", "answer": "I know nothing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c2", "question": "Which country's cuisine includes the dish called \"bibimbap\"?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339085", "question": "What is considered as the first daily comic strip in the US?", "answer": "Mutt and Jeff", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6b4abfb6c85e9e634ff44", "question": "What is a shark's skeleton made of?", "answer": "Cartilage", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339998", "question": "\"Citizens on Patrol\" and \"Mission to Moscow\" are subtitles of sequels to what 1980\u2019s series of movies?", "answer": "Police Academy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a976", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Althing?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d5", "question": "At the end of \"Planet of the Apes\" what monument protruded from the rocks?", "answer": "Statue of Liberty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964b", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1995 movie \"Babe\"?", "answer": "Pig", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b60a", "question": "What color are the standard mile marker signs used on the Interstate Highway System in the United States?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab13f6baab681b09292170", "question": "What car manufacturer was the first to mass-produce and equip a production vehicle with a V4 engine?", "answer": "Lancia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76ec4eec85e375820b2e0", "question": "Which country was formerly called Zaire?", "answer": "The Democratic Republic of the Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37c", "question": "Who developed the classification we use for clouds?", "answer": "Luke Howard", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339370", "question": "What movie won the Oscar for Best Visual Effects in 1978?", "answer": "Superman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad8f", "question": "Which Protestant Reformer outlawed the Feast of Saint Nicholas in 1545?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89b", "question": "How many points do you score for a bullseye in archery?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ef0a06d333868d34d777", "question": "What is primarily used to make traditional hummus?", "answer": "Chickpeas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdc143b469bb8041d07a085", "question": "Which U.S. best-selling wine is often referred to as \"over-oaked\" and \"not food-friendly\"?", "answer": "Chardonnay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c3", "question": "In what year did Martin Luther King Jr. deliver his \"I Have a  Dream\" speech?", "answer": "1963", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59564403803c1f1ebcc4a033", "question": "Ketchup was sold in the 1830\u2019s as what?", "answer": "Medicine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133960f", "question": "What 2005 movie stars Ellen Page and Sandra Oh?", "answer": "Hard Candy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb12065ff7d326b622a66", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for Curium?", "answer": "Cm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397d1", "question": "With what band did Gloria Estefan sing during the 1980s?", "answer": "Miami Sound Machine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59523dfa736d4be723796b49", "question": "What does the \"Calgary Stampede\" bills itself as?", "answer": "The Greatest Outdoor Show on Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febd3eb7e83c707845b2157", "question": "Red had how many parole hearings through out the course of the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Three", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2c1", "question": "In atmospheres, what is the equivalent of 760 milimeters of Mercury (mmHg)?", "answer": "1 atm", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59636c06967692ea851899a7", "question": "How many years after the 1990\u2019s movie \"Independence Day\", was sequel \"Independence Day: Resurgence\" released?", "answer": "20 years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5eb734555e259d7869087328", "question": "Which US president went on record saying that he wished he could\u2019ve hanged his vice president during his administration?", "answer": "Andrew Jackson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6007822ebd51d85e222ab654", "question": "What title was Henri Matisse's \"Harmony in Red\" originally commissioned under?", "answer": "The painting was originally commissioned in blue. Matisse was dissatisfied with the result and repainted the entire painting red.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6aac020565ad31a57c820", "question": "During the American Revolution, who was known as the Swamp Fox?", "answer": "Lt. Col. Francis Marion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59068223ff9c0647b50a809a", "question": "Which US Senator was nominated as Hillary Clinton\u2019s vice presidential running mate?", "answer": "Tim Kaine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339600", "question": "What movie based on a 1960's TV show was about a family's intergalactic journey through space?", "answer": "Lost in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0b", "question": "Hockey legend Wayne Gretzky was born in what year?", "answer": "1961", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc51", "question": "What year was Marmite first launched onto the market?", "answer": "1902", "category": "general"}]